Kedar Krishnan

116, 10 Ronayne street, Auckland Central, Auckland 1010

E: kedar.krishnan@gmail.com M: 027 431 5111

SUMMARY

I am a full stack developer with 12+ years of experience across banking, finance and telecom domain. My expertise lies in working on projects using Java, Spring, JavaScript, AngularJS, NodeJS, CSS, BIRT and Restful web services.

I'm an active proponent of Object oriented programming – I love the power of encapsulating the implementation details using Java classes and JavaScript objects, and the way restful services integrate the backend with the frontend.

My personal development project includes a content management system using Spring restful web services and tomcat for backend, and Angular JS with Node JS using Express module.

SKILLS

Java

Spring Framework

I have experience of using spring's web-MVC, transaction management and Spring AOP. I have exposure to spring annotations and in my opinion annotation and XML configuration should be used as mix instead of going with any one of the approach.

Testing

Most general testing I have approached with Junit. EasyMock usually supplements my Junit tests because it provides an easy way for replacement of a collaborator object. I have used Eclipse plugin EclEmma to identify areas of more attention when extending test suites, but in my experience, chasing test coverage numbers leads to brittle tests.

Front-End

I have excellent experience with JavaScript. JavaScript's prototype-based inheritance model is a little unusual, as are its block-scoping rules. I have used jQuery and AngularJS commercially and have recently started dabbling RxJS with in my free time.

Other Skills

I would be happy to discuss my commercial experience with and exposure to: Agile SCRUM, MySQL, Bootstrap, NodeJS, BIRT.

OPEN SOURCE AND COMMUNITY

infoGraph.js

A JavaScript charting module, used for displaying profile skills infograph on web page.

indian-states-cities

A NodeJS module for getting states and cities of India based on criteria.

Other projects

- My github page http://kedarkrishnan.github.io
- Web development project as a part of my assignment http://profile.kedar.xyz/queenstown
- Participated in GovHack 2016 Auckland. Awarded "Voted best embodiment of the Sprint of GovHack for amazing team work" http://2016.hackerspace.govhack.org/content/ptp

Writing

I am currently in process of publishing a series of tutorials a novice developer should know about a skill https://github.com/kedarkrishnan/Developers-Diary

WORK EXPERIENCE

Associate - Developer JP MORGAN; Oct 2008 - Jun 2016

Skills used: Java, Spring, BIRT, SCRUM, Git, Bootstrap, JavaScript, AngularJS, JQuery

Role overview: Senior Developer helping to design and architect a reporting engine using open source BIRT. Working with vendor teams, allocating and reviewing work done by team members. Originally employed to help build reports using licensed Actuate BIRT and parsing the data from a web service.

Interesting challenges: Migrating from licensed Actuate BIRT to open source BIRT saving around 2 million US\$ per year required creation of wrappers around BIRT runtime using Spring so as to add

more functionalities like administration, web service support, scheduling and storage.

Building interactive functionality on reports using Bootstrap, Javascript and Jquery so that users can change the structure of the reports at runtime.

Analyst Programmer SYNTEL; Jan 2006 – Oct 2008

Skills used: Java, Spring, CSS, HTML, JavaScript, JQuery

Role overview: Designing and developing customizable portal displaying dashboard for Syntel's Center of Excellence team. Working with clients for requirement gathering, creating technical analysis document (TAD).

Interesting challenges: Creation of Actuate COE portal, which is demoed to customers as a part of pre-sales not only needed to have dynamic functionality like customizable screens but also needed to look aesthetic.

Developer SEEINFOBIZ; Nov 2003 – Jan 2006

Skills used: Java, JSP, HTML, JavaScript

Role overview: Designing and developing customer-billing system for Telecommunication Company.

Interesting challenges: Understanding the raw billing files to write parsers to read the data and formatting the outputs for online as well as printing for 13 circles with different billing cycles and requirements needed the system to be customizable and also efficient to generate the require bills within the estimated time.

EDUCATION QUALIFICATION

Bachelor of Engineering

Mumbai University; 1997 - 2001